Spencer.max.rubin@gmail.com

248-763-9642

2733 La Bajada, Santa Fe, NM 87505

in linkedin.com/in/spencer-max-rubin/ \$\mathbf{O}\$ smrubin1987

SUMMARY

I am a Data Scientist with a Masters in Environmental Science and Policy, and over ten years of science research, data analysis, and data collection experiences. Seeking to solve complex business problems through the integration of data science, communication, and research. Currently growing my skills in statistical modeling and data science utilizing Python.

EMPLOYMENT

Battelle

Environmental Scientist · Oct. 2017 to Current · Santa Fe, NM

Science and land use permit and agreement management, technical and proposal writing, compliance oversight, data reporting and analysis, and database management for nation-wide 81-site NEON Environmental Observatory.

NEON, Inc.

Field Technician III · Sept. 2014 to Oct. 2017 · Denton, TX

Lead environmental field technician overseeing environmental data and sample collection, data quality control and entry, and management with a team of fifteen staff at two long-term field sites.

Colorado State University

Wetland Field Technician · June 2014 to Sept. 2014 · Ft. Collins, CO

Wetland field technician with Colorado Natural Heritage Program support remote wetland habitat surveys for soil, vegetation, and hydrologic parameters.

Robert H. Booher Consulting

Field Biologist · May 2013 to Sept. 2013 · Bakersfield, CA

Performed field surveys and wrote reports on habitat and species presence on dozens of oil and gas sites for endangered species.

Northern Arizona University

Graduate Researcher · Aug. 2010 to Dec. 2012 · Flagstaff, AZ

Teaching assistant for Environmental Science, Extreme Weather laboratories. Conducted field collections and analysis of lake and pond sediments for paleoecological research. Administrative assistant for Southern Colorado Plateau Network.

EDUCATION

Springboard Data Science Career Track: Certification · Sept. 2019 to Current

Northern Arizona University · 2012

MS Environmental Science & Policy

Teaching assistant: Environmental Science Laboratory, Extreme Weather

Graduate research assistant: paleoecological sediment extraction and fossil analysis.

Michigan State University · 2009

BS Plant Biology

Undergraduate research assistant: wetland soil analysis.

SKILLS

MICROSOFT:: Excel, Word, Teams, PowerPoint, SharePoint DATA SCIENCE:: Python, Pandas, Seaborn, SQL, Matplotlib

TECHNICAL WRITING: Proposals, Data Reporting, Contractual Support

PUBLIC SPEAKING: Data Visualizations, Meeting Facilitation, Telecommunications

PROJECTS

Colorado Natural Heritage Program (CHNP)

May 2014 to Sept. 2014

Wetland and riparian mapping and ecological sampling in southeastern Colorado.

National Ecological Observatory Network (NEON)

Sept. 2014 to Current

Long-term environmental data collection observatory funded through the National Science Foundation.

AWARDS

National Oceanic & Atmospheric Administration \cdot NOAA Science Communications Fellowship

Doris Duke Foundation · Doris Duke Conservation Fellowship

Battelle · Battelle Innvovation Gathering